lain Maitland

Fullstack Developer



About

13512 Gable Street

- Detroit Michigan MI 48212 US
- (737) 226-3943
- iainmaitland.com
- imaitland
- **y** iain_maitland

Web Development

Professional

React Rust Typescript Javascript NodeJS/Deno GraphQL

MySql/NoSql/Postgres

DevOps

Professional

AWS Docker Git

Languages

English (Native speaker)

Interests

Art

Photography Poetry Writing

Summary

lain hails from Manchester, England. He has a degree from the University of Cambridge, in Law and History of Art, and 5 years experience as a frontend and fullstack web developer. Before going freelance as a full stack developer he worked as an early employee for Steem, building user-facing apps and backend micro-services, with React, Typescript and NodeJS on their blockchain / social media platform as it scaled to 1M+ users. More recently using Rust, he has made a static site generator, while also working on an image hoster service and a networked key-value store. He is excited by any opportunity to use Rust's powerful features in production, particularly when it can complement his frontend experience with Typescript, Javascript and React.

Experience

Freelance 05/2020 - Present

Develop useful software for a variety of clients Fullstack developer

Worked as a lead developer with a local and remote team of graphic and product designers to implement solutions for creative and b2b software briefs for a range of clients including General Motors, Amazon, Google and Ford.

- https://hobbes.work a portfolio site for an UI/UX studio using a customized headless CMS and a React/Typescript frontend
- https://means.tv a media streaming platform with subscription features
- A custom CRM for General Motors in React and NodeJS used at Dealerships and special events nationwide

Steemit.com 03/2018 - 05/2020

Developed applications for the Steem blockchain Fullstack Developer

Worked as part of a remote agile team with 3 other developers, to develop and scale open source blockchain software (https://github.com/steemit) used by millions of users and processing millions of dollars in cryptocurrency transactions.

- Built the most popular frontend (React/Typescript) for the Steem blockchain, including authorization, market trading, and cryptocurrency wallet features
- https://steemit.com A reddit clone written in React, scaling from a few thousand to millions of users internationally
- https://signup.steemit.com/ User creation service or 'faucet,' onboarded more than a million new users
- https://wallet.steemit.com Feature-rich cryptocurrency wallet including trading, exchange and withdrawal

Quikly 05/2017 - 03/2018

Developed an administration dashboard in React Frontend Developer

Worked as lead React developer as part of an agile team on b2b dashboard software.

- Build out a GraphQL api in Ruby-on-rails to drive the react frontend
- Advocate for Typescript adoption within the company

Penske Media Corporation

01/2016 - 05/2017

Developed CMSs and frontends for magazines like rollingstone.com and variety.com Frontend Developer

Worked as part of an agile team with 2 other developers, developed CMS backends in Contentful, Wordpress and Drupal and frontends in React

Lead pivot from traditional CMS instances to a headless model

Education